Guide to the A. Poulin Papers and BOA Editions Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 1997 Acquisition, 1951-1996; 3; 39.38; (44 boxes)
  - Various BOA publications: New Poetry from BOA Editions, Ltd. Fall 1995 [2 copies]; BOA Fall/Winter 1994, New Titles and Complete Backlist [1 copy], 1994-1995 (Box 123)
  - Knott, Bill: The Quicken Tree: Poems. Page proofs, unbound manuscript copy, [1995] (Box 123)
  - Color photo of Edvard Munch painting, cover art for Natalie Kenvin's Bruise Theory, undated (Box 123)
  - Envelope entitled, "TSP and CSP and JSP", undated (Box 123)
  - Piccione, Anthony: For the Kingdom: Poems, Unbound manuscript copy. "Lost Foul Proofs", [1994] (Box 123)
  - Deming, Richard, translation: 20 Love Poems And A Song Of Despair by Pablo Neruda. Unbound manuscript copy, undated (Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous BOA business, BOA correspondence, [1994] (Box 123)
  - BOA business, correspondence, miscellaneous, [1994-1995] (Box 123)
  - Addonizio, Kim: Jimmy and Rita, 1 bound, 2 unbound manuscript copies and other miscellaneous, [1995] (Box 123)
  - Various BOA correspondence, [1995]; 3 (Box 123)
  - Empty envelope, marked "R. Lyon", undated (Box 123)
  - Piccione, Anthony: For the Kingdom, bound manuscript copy, uncorrected proofs, correspondence and other miscellaneous materials, [1993-1995] (Box 123)
  - Laux, Dorianne: publications material, correspondence and other miscellaneous materials including 3 issues of "Yellow Silk" w/ reviews of Laux's work, [1994-1995] (Box 123)
  - Envelope titled, "Cover letters from manuscripts to us-1995" (Box 123)
  - Wright, Terry: What the Black Box Said, bound manuscript copy, [1995 September] (Box 123)
  - Various authors' and illustrators' submissions, [1995]; 3 (Box 123)
  - Perricone, C.: A Summer of Monkey Poems, unbound manuscript copy, [1995] (Box 124)
  - Cirino, Leonard J.: Notes from an Off- White Room and Other Work, unbound manuscript copy, [1995 January] (Box 124)
  - Edwards, Shirley R.: Nineteen Sixty- Four, bound manuscript copy, [1994 July] (Box 124)
  - Di Pasquale, Emanuel: Praise for One Day, manuscript copy, [1995 June] (Box 124)
  - Publishing notes, correspondence, and Heyen, William: Crazy Horse in Stillness, manuscript copy, c. 1996: "3/3/95 Corrected Mscpt.", [1995-1996]; 3 (Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, cover art, and related ephemera, 1992-1995, undated (Box 124)
  - Ceramic skull, undated (Box 125)
  - Elements of Literature (first course), binder, 1998 (Box 126)
    Related Materials
    There are two audiocassettes related to this material. They can be found in box 39. The reference numbers are as follows: ff34472a223b845c5cab6912e15ddb10 and 4a463f03348df9c6b2f0868ae966434b.
  - Elements of Literature (first course) (1 of 2 audiocassettes), 1993; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091397423)
    The contents of this audiocassette are listed below. This tape is considered commercial and has not been digitized.
    1. Princess
    2. "Tom Sawyer" (excerpt)
    3. The Glove and the Lions
    4. After Twenty Years: A Mother in Mannville
    5. Daedalus
    6. The Cremation of Sam McGee
    7. The Highwayman
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    This audiocassette is related to a binder of material titled "Elements of Literature: First Course" found in Box 126, reference number 1873.
  - Elements of Literature (first course) (2 of 2 audiocassettes), 1993; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091397431)
    There is a list of contents included below. This audiocassette is considered a commercial tape and it has not been digitized.
    Side 3 / Side 4
    1. Birdfoot's Grampa
    2. The Tale of Custard the Dragon
    3. Daisy
    4. Bats
    5. Giant Thunder
    6. Cat & the Weather
    7. The Boy and the Wolf
    8. The Lost Parrot
    9. Madam and the Rent Man
    10. The Pasture
    11. The Flower-Fed Buffaloes
    12. 4 Daughters
    13. The Listerners
    14. The Monkey's Paw
    15. Phaethon
    16. Young Ladies Don't Slay Dragons
    17. Prometheus
    18. Bury Me Not on the Lone Prairie
    19. The Crane Wife
    20. He Was a Small Child
    21. "Treasure Island" (excerpt)
  - Elements of Literature (second course), 1998 (Box 126)
  - Freeing Eurydice a novel by Bertrand Mathieu, undated (Box 127)
  - Job application letters and resumes to the BOA Editions Limited, 1991-1992 (Box 127)
  - Miscellaneous poetry, letters and catalogs, 1992 (Box 127)
  - Consortium, 1994-1995 (Box 128)
  - Commonweal, 1995 (Box 128)
  - Staff Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 128)
  - These Upraised Hands, poems by William Patrick, 1995 (Box 128)
  - Dreams When We Are Not Asleep, poems by William Patrick, 1993 (Box 128)
  - The Terrible Stories, poems by Lucille Clifton, 1995 (Box 128)
  - Word Wounds and Water Flowers, Poems by Daniela Gioseffi, 1995 (Box 128)
  - The Quicken Tree, poems by Bill Knott, 1994 (Box 128)
  - Poems by William Hayen, 1994 (Box 128)
  - Changes for Piccione manuscript, undated (Box 128)
  - For the Kingdom, writings of Anthony Piccione, 1992 (Box 128)
  - The Island of Birds, poems of William Patrick, 1995 (Box 128)
  - Press releases, 1973-1979 (Box 128)
  - Broadside, On Hearing That My Poems Were Being Studied In a Distant Place, by Hyam Plutzik, 1982 (Box 129)
  - CAP VI. Galleys/Tick offs; page proofs, 1995; 5 (Box 129)
  - CAP VI. Galleys/Tick offs; page proofs, 1995; 5 (Box 130)
  - Poems by Diann Blakely Shoaf, and Mechanicals for Nobody Lives on Arthur Godfrey Boulevard, Poems by Gerald Costanzo, [circa 1992] (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Northwest Poets and Artists Calendar, 1994 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Bookcovers, undated; 12 (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - Computer media
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Poems, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0001; 1 (Box 132)
    - Fuehrer Bunker final (9 files), 1997-ycal-0521-a-0002; 1 (Box 132)
    - Feuhrer Bunker final (fonts), 1997-ycal-0521-a-0003; 1 (Box 132)
    - For The Kingdom Piccione, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0004; 1 (Box 132)
    - Naomi's book table of contents, etc. at end of ms. Microsoftword 4.1, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0005; 1 (Box 132)
    - FONTS, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0006; 1 (Box 132)
    - MECHANICALS AND ART, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0007; 1 (Box 132)
    - QUICKEN TREE, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0008; 1 (Box 132)
    - QUICKEN TREE, 1997-ycal-0521-a-0009; 1 (Box 132)